We got Dr. Isaacson.
All right. You guys go check it out.
I'm expected at the office.
Hubb?
Get ready for the smackdown.
He's gonna come at you hard.
-== [ www.OpenSubtitles.org ] ==-
- Who is it?
- N.Y.P.D.
- Dr. Isaacson?
- Yeah.
Detective Ornelas. N.Y.P.D.
This is my partner. Detective Ward.
- We'd like to ask a couple questions.
- Why?
What do you want?
Why are you here?
Calm down. We just wanna ask you
a few questions about a patient.
Patient? What patient?
Come on. you know what time it is?
Listen. I'm sorry. I must go.
I really didn't do anything.
- I'm sorry. Good night.
- Doctor. if we could...
Douche bag's pinned out of his mind.
He thinks we're here to bust him.
Dr. Isaacson. please.
We have reason to believe your life
is in danger. grave danger.
We think one of your patients
is trying to kill you.
Kill me?
I'm Agent Salinger with Interpol.
We're assisting in this manhunt.
Why would a patient wanna kill me?
I'm an orthopedist.
This man's a psychotic. He's already
butchered seven doctors in Europe.
We got some serious evidence
to suggest you may be next.
Have you ever seen this man?
No. no. I don't think so.
Does the name Timothy Sherwood
mean anything to you. doctor?
No. How do you know
he's a patient of mine?
We have his footprint.
Yeah. the shoe was manufactured
by AGM Biomechanics...
...exclusively for the Isaacson Institute.
model K-A-F-O 1-2-1.
K-A-F-O 1-2-1?
We started prescribing
that three years ago.
We've used it on hundreds
of our patients.
Well. then we're gonna need
to review all of your files.
Right now?
Doctor. we need to find this man
before he finds you.
- What are you trying to do here. Ella?
- I'm doing my job.
You have any idea of the shitstorm
you've gotten me into?
- We're just trying to get to the truth.
- I get it.
You need to remember there's what
people wanna hear. wanna believe...
...there's everything else.
then there's the truth.
And since when is that okay?
I can't believe you're saying this to me.
The truth means responsibility. Arnie.
Exactly. which is why
everyone dreads it.
Look...
The IBBC is using one assassin
for all their hits...
...and we've tracked him here
to New York.
This guy can bury them.
They want me to put a gun
to your head.
You don't find this guy.
and I mean quick...
...they're gonna make me
pull the trigger.
- Do you want dessert?
- No. thank you.
I'd like one.
This is a game that rewards
patience and balance.
You must think like a man of action
and act like a man of thought.
Gentlemen.
Sorry to disturb you at home.
I'm afraid this couldn't wait.
Yes?
Salinger was in Milan.
Whitman too.
They have the scent.
It's only a matter of time
before they find our consultant.
Any recommendations?
I strongly advise
against doing anything...
... that would heighten your exposure
right now.
Wilhelm. we've leveraged ourselves
over the edge.
If we don't meet the delivery date.
buyers will cancel orders...
... our plans will implode...
... and this bank will be left
a bill it cannot pay.
Heightening exposure
is the least of our problems.
I agree.
We're about to engage Calvini's sons.
We can't allow anyone
to put our agenda at risk.
We must sever all ties
with the consultant.
Consider the mark. gentlemen.
Doing this could be
a very messy affair.
Well. then make it one.
I don't know why you pay me
to advise on these matters.
It is clear that you don't want my
counsel. only my corroboration.
Really. Wilhelm. We've had
just about all we can take of you.
Yes. I've had about all I can take
of myself.
How would you like us to proceed?
Cassian. what does one do when
there's no way out of a situation?
If there's no way out...
...the best thing is
to find a way further in.
- Fucking disgusting. you know that?
- What are you. my mother?
No. but I could be your old man
for all you know. asshole.
Hey. doc.
Gabriel Hansen?
I don't know.
My associate handled this.
Well. the address
is a post-office box...
...and he paid cash
for all of his medical bills.
There are no diagnostic photos.
Why?
- I don't know.
- Is there a number?
Yeah. 212-157-6421.
It's a dead line.
I'll put a call in to Hubby.
have her run it down.
See if we can't get a crack warrant
for the P.O. Box in Jersey.
What do all these GT's
next to the appointment entries mean?
We have a kickback account
with Go Taxi...
...and they indicate when we
use their service for a patient.
Hey. Hubb says you caught a lead.
Yeah. we've got an address.
We're en route.
- What is it?
- Well. it could be him.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Well. they gotta bring him in now.
This is our last shot.
What do you mean. "our last shot"?
Arnie and I had it out last night.
and our clock's run out.
If we don't get this guy right now.
it's over.
Well. it better be him. then.
I'm here. Yeah.
I know that.
This is definitely the right address?
Checked the log myself. This is where
they dropped him off every time.
Well. he could be anywhere.
- What do you think he was doing?
- Beats the shit out of me.
It's a big. empty lot.
Well. I'm starving. I'm gonna
get something. You want anything?
Yeah. a coffee. black.
I'm going back down to
headquarters after this.
Okay. all right.
Right. bye.
How long do you think
this has been like this?
I don't know. but we need to find out.
The doctor's records say
the last time...
...somebody got dropped off here
was five weeks ago.
I mean. there's not even
a temporary office or anything.
- How you doing?
Son of a bitch.
What's the matter?
I just made our perp.
Eleven o'clock. blue overcoat.
- You sure that's him?
- A hundred percent.
- Where did he come from?
- Shit if I know.
I'm at the counter and
I see him rolling past the window.
- Wanna go for the collar?
- No.
We tail him. find out where he sleeps.
then take him down.
A. B. C. Keep the box tight.
- Five-oh-two-six. Designator?
- Samuel Koppler.
Message:
Your uncle
wishes to see you immediately.
Response?
The Guggenheim. fifth floor
of the rotunda. 40 minutes.
- Hi. how you doing?
- Hello.
N.Y.P.D. I need to
speak to your security chief.
Okay. one moment.
Rick?
How you doing? Detective Ornelas.
I need to be able to clear security.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
We're clear.
Directly behind me.
There you go. Thank you.
Who's the old scag
sitting next to him?
I don't know. but I saw him at the
bank's headquarters in Luxembourg.
You don't look well today.
We all begin better than we end.
What would you prefer your ending
to be like?
Oh. more purposeful.
and certainly more climactic.
A finale.
Circumstances can always
be arranged.
As much as the thought
appeals to me...
...l'm afraid your consideration
is needed elsewhere.
- What is this?
- Salinger.
The method and manner
is entirely up to you.
Your principle would simply like him
to vanish without a trace.
- Any other provisions?
- Yes.
No mistakes.
I'll follow.
- Where's Iggy going?
- Following a new lead.
Shit.
We gotta go.
N.Y.P.D. Lock your hands
behind your head.
Do it now.
They'll never let you bring me in.
Do it. or I'll take you down.
- Cuffs.
- On the belt.
There's a guy right up there.
- Where'd he...?
- Up there! Up there!
Get down!
- God! Oh. my God!
- It's okay.
Down there.
Shit.
Drop the gun.
- If I drop the gun. we'll both die.
- I said. drop the gun!
They're here for me but they'll kill
you too. Now help me get this off.
I can't breathe.
Stairs.
- Fuck.
- You okay?
The ramp is the only way out.
Hey.
Don't you fucking dare.
I'm calling from the dark side.
- Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
- I'm calling from the...
Get back.
I told you.
What? You told me what?
They'd never let you bring me in.
Fuck. fuck.
Move away from the building.
Can everybody please
move away from the building?
They know you're coming.
We gotta hurry.
- Where'd they find him?
- Sitting on a bench near the reservoir.
- Has he said anything yet?
- Nothing. He's pretty shaken up.
- Who else knows he's here?
- Everyone. Nothing I could do.
Heavies from the Bureau
and Justice are on their way.
- with an unidentified third man.
- How long do I have?
- Five. 10 minutes. max.
- wanted for questioning
in an ongoing investigation.
Now. a Guggenheim employee tells me
that while they were in the museum...
This isn't over.
Are you sure about this?
Just read it.
- They recognize you?
- Don't think so.
Back it up!
- ... screens came crashing down.
- How you doing?
- There was glass everywhere.
- As compared to what?
And just on the ground.
When you heard all of this
commotion. did you think...?
Anything you need. Ellie.
just let me know.
- Thanks.
- I just heard gunshots.
And people were hit
and screaming...
... and people just started running
out the door...
... and I didn't know
what was going on.
You okay?
Yeah.
You flip this guy.
You make sure my partner
wasn't killed for nothing.
I know that... I think random people
were going down and...
I mean. there was police running up
as other people were going down.
You ready for this?
Good evening. Colonel Wexler.
I'm Agent Louis Salinger.
I know who you are.
Of course you do.
I was at the Guggenheim
this afternoon.
The assassin you met with...
... I know you were his handler.
I know you arranged for him
to be killed at the behest of the bank...
...because I was obviously
getting too close.
But if a hit team at the Guggenheim
is what happens...
...because I was
getting too close to him...
...what do you think the bank'll do
when it realizes how close I am to you?
Death comes for us all.
Agent Salinger.
But based on everything
I've read about you...
...you seem like the kind of man...
...who aspired to die
for something more than this.
Well. this is the difference
between truth and fiction.
Fiction has to make sense.
I'm confused. colonel.
Why would a tried
and true communist...
...a hardliner that spent 30 years
in the Stasi...
...fighting against the evils
of capitalism...
Why would this man waste his
final days working for an institution...
...that was the very embodiment
of everything he once despised?
You dedicated your life
to the communist ideal.
You sacrificed everything
for the good of the party.
For what?
You lost your wife to betrayal...
...your daughter to suicide...
...and when the Wall fell.
your whole life fell apart with it.
You know nothing about me.
I was lost long before the Wall fell.
I was once destined to become
a man much like yourself.
True-hearted...
...determined...
...full of purpose.
But...
...character is easier kept
than recovered.
We cannot control
the things life does to us.
They are done before you know it.
and once they are done...
...they make you do other things...
...until at last.
everything comes between you...
...and the man you wanted to be.
No.
We all have choices in life.
You made yours.
Sometimes a man
can meet his destiny...
...on the road he took to avoid it.
Skarssen and that bank need to
answer for what they've done.
They have to be brought to justice.
You can help me do that.
Justice...
...is not possible.
Why not?
Because. Agent Salinger...
...your idea of justice is an illusion.
Understand the very system
that you serve and protect...
... will never allow anything to happen
to Skarssen or the bank.
On the contrary.
The system guarantees
the IBBC's safety...
...because everyone is involved.
What do you mean. "everyone"?
Hezbollah.
CIA.
The Columbian drug cartels.
Russian organized crime.
Governments of Iran. Germany.
China. your government.
Every multinational corporation.
every one.
They all need banks like the IBBC...
...so that they can operate
within the black and gray latitudes.
And this is why
your investigative efforts...
...have either been ignored
or undermined...
...and why you and I
will be quietly disposed of...
...before any case against the bank
ever reaches a court of law.
So. what are we all
supposed to do?
We just supposed to give up...
...and accept that
this is the way of the world?
I'm not gonna do that.
I still believe... I know...
...that there has to be a way
to bring down this bank...
...and you are gonna help me.
You understand...
...if you really want to
stop the IBBC...
...you won't be able to do it within the
boundaries of your system of justice.
You will have to go outside.
Once you do...
...there will always be
collateral damage.
Yes.
Should you sacrifice your own ideals
for the greater good?
That's a difficult choice.
one I understand all too well...
...but as you so eloquently put it...
...sometimes a man
can meet his destiny...
...on the road he took to avoid it.
What?
What are you doing?
I think it's time for you to leave.
- Leave? What are you talking about?
- You know what I'm talking about.
No way. Lou.
No fucking way.
You've already got him turned.
Now go back in there
and get him to come in on his own.
We can use everything.
We'll blow this whole thing wide open.
- I don't think so.
- Why not?
I'm not gonna make
the same mistake twice.
- I can protect him. Lou.
- No. you can't. They'll get to him.
If they can't. they'll get to you.
If they can't get to you.
they'll get to your family.
I can't just walk away from this.
You're walking away
so I don't have to.
How can you trust him?
That relic in there
is looking for redemption.
I'm the only one
who can give it to him.
Then who gives it to you
when this is all over?
You need to cut me loose.
Tell them I escaped from custody.
whatever you have to.
Just use my history.
They'll believe you.
- I don't know.
- Ella. listen to me.
Sometimes the hardest thing...
...is to know which bridge to cross
and which to burn.
I'm the one you burn.
We've been waiting here
for an hour.
I'm sorry. Martin. but none of us
have been able to reach them.
Unfortunately. Mario and Enzo Calvini
are not known for their punctuality.
They do realize this is the closing?
Mr. White...
...l've been instructed to escort you
and your associates from the building.
Please gather your materials
and come with me.
- Instructed by whom?
- Please. if you could just comply.
Our father
never trusted these people.
Thank you for telling us the truth.
Had you not come forward...
...we would have made
a terrible mistake today.
I'm just glad I could be of service.
I don't know. Jonas. I was told nothing.
I was simply thrown out.
They know.
Look. I can't discuss this right now.
I'll call you when I'm in the air.
Welcome to World News.
I'm Tristana Moore.
We're live today in the
Democratic Republic of Niberia.
As we go on air. we're getting reports
that thousands of troops...
... loyal to General Charles Motomba's
Revolutionary Freedom Front...
... are moving towards
the capital of Dénué.
According to eyewitnesses.
several explosions have been heard...
... and there've been heavy outbreaks
of gunfire in many parts of the city.
The people of Niberia
have suffered greatly.
It is time to begin a new chapter
in our country's history.
We will not stop
until national liberation...
... and the restoration of nationhood...
News about Martin?
He didn't show up at his hotel
or at the airport.
The Italian police have been unable
to locate his car or driver.
I think Enzo and Mario Calvini
are sending us a message.
How could they possibly
have found out?
This is precisely
what we pay you to know.
We're out of time and options.
- We must make the deal with Sunay.
- How can we trust this man?
The Israeli government
is his biggest customer.
Why would he agree...
...to help us provide missiles
to the Iranians and the Syrians...
...that have a first-strike capability
against the Israelis?
I know Sunay.
I believe he has every intention...
...of selling you
the guidance systems...
...because he's already provided
the Israelis...
...with the countermeasures
to defeat them.
Would the Turk really play
such a dangerous game?
We are.
The only way we can make this work...
...is to guarantee...
...that Sunay keeps this information
in complete confidence.
If our buyers find out the missiles are
worthless. they'll pull all their orders...
...and this bank will be left insolvent.
Have him here
by tomorrow afternoon.
Tomorrow he's going to
a funeral service for his cousin.
He'll be unavailable till Monday.
Unless of course.
you'd be willing to attend.
Make the call.
Get me Ahmet Sunay.
It's tomorrow.
It's right there.
Do you want to be escorted?
We'll be fine. thank you.
The Sunay funeral. please.
It will be over soon.
You may wait here.
- Is there a bathroom I could use?
- Just over there.
- I won't be a moment.
- Right.
- The signal?
- Good.
The Sunay funeral. please.
- Where'd you put the spike?
- Inside the lapel of his jacket.
The lawyer?
White?
He's gone.
I told you. there will always
be collateral damage...
...when you take matters
into your own hands.
Your plan is working.
It has left Skarssen
with only one option.
Record the conversation
and you'll gain your end.
Sure they'll talk about Sunay's deal
with Israel and the countermeasures?
It is the key issue.
Once you let the Iranians
and Syrians...
...hear that the missiles are completely
useless against the Israelis...
...they will cancel their orders
and the IBBC will collapse.
- Wilhelm.
- Ahmet.
It's been a long time.
Yes.
My sympathies for the loss
of your cousin.
Thank you.
Jonas Skarssen. Ahmet Sunay.
If you'd simply come to me in the
beginning. it would have been better.
Midday prayers will begin soon.
Should take a short time
to settle on the broad strokes.
The rest can be sorted out
at your leisure.
We have 10 minutes.
Wilhelm. would you mind
if I spoke to Mr. Sunay alone?
I believe I understand
the particulars of your situation.
Perhaps we should discuss this
in a more private place.
Yes. of course.
Allow me to show you something
very special.
Something that very few outsiders
know exists.
It's my understanding that the product
you purchased are the XW-41 s.
After you.
Yes. Forty-two hundred units.
What kind of guidance
are they currently equipped...?
They all need to be upgraded
with VOLCON systems.
Launch platforms?
Ground-based vehicles
and fixed-wing aircraft.
So you understand
I have a terminal deadline.
First of February. yes.
- Can you meet it?
- To be sure.
But you must arrange for the
end-user certificates. transport...
We'll arrange for it all.
Where would the work be done?
Cyprus. I've a facility there.
We would start retrofitting the worms
within a day of their arrival.
So if you deliver them to me
within the next two weeks...
... we'll meet your deadline.
I'm concerned that we limit any and all
knowledge of your involvement.
If we structure my involvement
through a thick veil of shells...
... I don't foresee any complications.
- Sorry?
- You. Come here now.
Usually we would involve
our import partners from Russia.
What? I'm just a tourist.
- Now. you must leave.
- Could you get that light out of...?
Get your fucking...
So. shall we discuss numbers?
There is a more salient deal point...
...that needs to be resolved
before we can do that.
And what point is that?
The point of fidelity.
I know you provided
the Israeli government...
...with the countermeasures
to this guidance system.
Last year alone...
...I did more than 300 million
in business with the Israelis.
I would never put that at risk.
How can I trust you not to divulge
this information to anyone else?
It's mutual interest. not trust...
...that will be the bond
of our relationship.
Your compensation will be held
in an escrow account.
- released until our clients pay
in full.
And those are the terms.
The payout structure...
The transfers will be begun
by tomorrow morning.
Ehames will contact you with
the number for the escrow account.
So ends the bloody business
of the day.
We're closed. I need you and Ehames
here tomorrow...
...to work out all the details
with Sunay's people.
Yes. We're on our way home.
Wilhelm?
Wake up.
Who are you?
I'm Louis Salinger.
You don't have the authority
to arrest me.
Who said anything
about arresting you?
- What do you want?
- I want some fucking justice.
Wait. wait. Wait.
Executing me won't change anything.
There will be 100 other bankers
to take my place.
Everything will continue.
The only thing you'll succeed in doing
is to satisfy your own blood lust.
And you know it.
With compliments of Enzo
and Mario Calvini.
Thank you.
Subtitles by LeapinLar
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org